Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're going to go back to the movies, but this time we're going to do it a little
今天我们要回到电影话题，但这次我们会有点
bit different.
不同。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to be listening as two movie critics offer their opinion on the latest release.
我们将听到两位影评人对最新上映电影的看法。
Alright, so we're going to be learning how to criticize or give your opinions about something.
好的，所以我们要学习如何批评或表达对某事的意见。
That's right.
没错。
And here we're talking movies, but a lot of this language can be used to offer your criticism
这里我们谈论的是电影，但很多这种语言也可以用来表达你对文学、艺术或其他艺术追求的批评
or ideas on literature or art or other artistic pursuits.
或想法。
Okay, so before we listen to this dialogue for the first time, let's take a look at vocabulary
好的，在我们第一次听这段对话之前，先来看看词汇
preview.
预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Well, we're going to look at one word here that we will hear in the dialogue and it is
嗯，我们要看一个在对话中会听到的词，那就是
erudite.
erudite。
Erudite.
Erudite。
Okay, so this word erudite.
好的，所以这个词erudite。
Some people pronounce it erudite.
有些人发音为erudite。
That's true.
没错。
And basically it's an adjective describing someone who has a lot of knowledge about a
基本上它是一个形容词，描述某人对某个
subject.
主题有很多知识。
Okay, so an erudite in engineering.
好的，所以一个博学的工程专家。
Yes, or an erudite professor.
是的，或者一位博学的教授。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So that's the word that we're going to preview today.
这就是我们今天要预览的词。
And now let's listen to our dialogue and find out what movie they are criticizing.
现在让我们听一下对话，看看他们在批评哪部电影。
Welcome back movie lovers to another premiere movie review.
欢迎回来，电影爱好者们，来到另一场首映电影评论。
My name is Richard Clark and I am joined today by the very erudite David Watson.
我是Richard Clark，今天和我一起的是非常博学的David Watson。
Thank you, Dick.
谢谢你，Dick。
Today we're going to talk about the movie Lion King.
今天我们要谈论电影《狮子王》。
Tell me, what is your impression of this film?
告诉我，你对这部电影的印象是什么？
Well, I think this film is simply a fable depicting man's eternal greed for power.
嗯，我认为这部电影只是一个寓言，描绘了人类对权力永恒的贪婪。
And in my opinion, it's a very fine film.
在我看来，这是一部非常好的电影。
Even despite the accusations of plagiarism of traditional folk tales from other countries,
尽管有抄袭其他国家传统民间故事的指控，
the musical score was amazing.
但配乐非常出色。
The animation was very well done and the story was simply enchanting.
动画做得很好，故事也很迷人。
I think otherwise.
我持不同意见。
Even though the animation was technically strong and as you say, the score and songs
尽管动画技术上很扎实，而且如你所说，配乐和歌曲
performed by Elton John were great.
埃尔顿·约翰的表演非常棒。
The film lacks certain originality.
这部电影缺乏一定的原创性。
It lacked heart.
它缺少情感内核。
And I would dare to say it was too predictable.
我敢说它太 predictable 了。
Predictable?
predictable？
How?
怎么 predictable 了？
Come on, Dave.
得了吧，Dave。
It's a G-rated movie.
这是部 G 级电影。
It's for the kids.
是给孩子们看的。
It's not a thriller.
又不是惊悚片。
Well, that's just it.
嗯，问题就在这儿。
It did have some very dramatic and intense scenes.
它确实有一些非常戏剧化和紧张的场景。
For example, when Mufasa dies or the dark, grim portrayal of Scar.
比如木法沙去世，或者刀疤那阴暗、冷酷的刻画。
Even so, the film is linear.
即便如此，这部电影的剧情是线性的。
Mufasa dies.
木法沙死了。
Simba runs away thinking it's his fault.
辛巴跑开，以为是自己害的。
Falls in love and returns to retake what's rightfully his.
坠入爱河，然后回来夺回本该属于他的东西。
It's just too cliche.
这太老套了。
How can it be cliche?
怎么会老套呢？
It's a fable.
这是个寓言故事。
It's telling a time-honored story.
它在讲述一个经久不衰的故事。
The movie makes a point of how the hunger of power leads to corruption and teaches children
这部电影强调了权力欲望如何导致腐败，并教导孩子们
of the value of respect, life, and love.
尊重、生命和爱的价值。
You have always been so soft, Dick.
你一直这么心软，Dick。
Open your heart, Dave.
敞开心扉吧，Dave。
Don't shut us out.
别把我们拒之门外。
Anyway, that's all for today, folks.
好了，各位，今天就到这里。
Join us next time as we talk about How to Lose a Guy in 10 Days.
下次我们聊聊《十天丢个郎》，记得加入我们。
I'm sure you'll love that one, Dick.
我相信你一定会喜欢那部的，Dick。
All right.
好吧。
So The Lion King, one of my all-time favorites.
所以《狮子王》，我最爱的电影之一。
A very good movie and, well, mixed feelings about it, right?
一部非常好的电影，嗯，对它感觉复杂，对吧？
Some people think it's good.
有些人觉得它好。
Other people think it's not that good.
有些人觉得它没那么好。
I'm in the good camp, as you know.
我站在觉得它好的一边，你知道的。
But anyway, there's tons of really useful and quite difficult language here.
但不管怎样，这里有很多非常有用且相当难的语言点。
So why don't we look at that now in Language Takeaway.
所以我们不如在“语言摘录”环节来看看。
Language Takeaway.
语言摘录。
All right.
好的。
On Language Takeaway today, we have five words and we can start with the first one.
今天的“语言摘录”环节，我们有五个词，先从第一个开始。
So the first critic said that this was a movie depicting man's eternal greed for power.
所以第一位评论家说，这是一部描绘人类对权力永恒贪婪的电影。
Depicting.
描绘。
To depict.
All right.
好的。
So this word, depict, it sounds a little bit strange.
所以这个词，depict，听起来有点奇怪。
So before we explain it, let's take a look at some examples.
所以在解释它之前，我们先看一些例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I don't really like the way that novel depicted the role of women in society.
我不太喜欢那部小说描绘女性在社会中角色的方式。
It was pretty sexist.
它相当性别歧视。
Example two.
例子二。
A film depicts the realities of war very accurately.
一部电影非常准确地描绘了战争的现实。
Example three.
例子三。
Apparently this image here is depicting some of the most well-known scenes from Australian
显然，这张图片描绘了澳大利亚一些最著名的场景，
history.
历史。
All right.
好的。
So depicting.
所以是描绘。
I can basically understand that this means to show something.
我基本上能理解，这意味着展示某物。
Now we can notice that the word depict has this short little word picked in there that
现在我们可以注意到，单词 depict 里面包含了一个短小的词，听起来像 picture。
sounds like picture.
当我们想到描绘时，通常是在图片、书籍或绘画中。
And when we think about depicting, we're often thinking about in a picture or in a book or
所以在这种情况下，故事是在电影中被描绘的，对吧？
in a painting.
没错。
So in this case, the story is depicted in a movie, right?
所以你可以看到它。
That's right.
基本上就是一幅画面。
So you can see it.
完全正确。
It's a picture, basically.
好的。
Exactly.
很好。
All right.
所以是描绘。
Very good.
好的，继续，评论家还谈到了对电影反派角色刀疤的阴郁刻画。
So to depict.
刀疤。
Well, moving on, the critic also talked about the grim portrayal of the villain of the movie,
没错。
Scar.
所以是阴郁的刻画。
That's right.
一个阴郁的刻画。
So grim portrayal.
好的。
A grim portrayal.
我们先看看 grim 这个词。
Okay.
当某物是 grim 时，它非常令人不快、不舒服，甚至想到它都让人震惊。
Let's look at the word grim first.
好的。
When something is grim, it's really unpleasant or uncomfortable or even shocking to think
所以我们会用一些阴郁的东西。
about.
好的。
Okay.
所以我们会用一些阴郁的东西。
So we're going to use something that is grim.
好的。
Now what about portrayal?
那“portrayal”是什么意思呢？
Really close to depict.
非常接近“描绘”的意思。
A portrayal is something that shows or describes something, especially like in a book or in
“Portrayal”是指展示或描述某事物的东西，尤其是在书中、
a picture or in a play.
图片或戏剧里。
Okay.
好的。
So a portrayal.
所以是“portrayal”。
I guess we can relate it again to a portrait.
我想我们可以把它和“portrait”（肖像）联系起来。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So portrayal.
所以是“portrayal”。
Now we can also use this as a verb, to portray.
我们也可以把它用作动词，“to portray”。
So this movie portrays man's eternal greed.
所以这部电影描绘了人类永恒的贪婪。
Okay.
好的。
So we can use this as a noun or as a verb.
所以我们可以把它用作名词或动词。
That's right.
没错。
So moving on with our third word today, we have an enchanting movie.
那么继续我们今天的第三个词，我们有一个“enchanting movie”。
That's right.
没错。
The story was simply enchanting.
这个故事简直令人着迷。
Okay.
好的。
So if something is enchanting.
所以如果某事物是“enchanting”。
It's really attractive and beautiful and interesting and it holds your attention.
它非常吸引人、美丽、有趣，并且能抓住你的注意力。
Okay.
好的。
It holds your attention.
它抓住你的注意力。
So it's something very nice.
所以是非常好的东西。
Something that is enchanting has to be nice.
“Enchanting”的东西必须是好的。
That's right.
没错。
And it has this sense of magic around it.
而且它带有一种魔幻的感觉。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So an enchanting moment.
所以是“an enchanting moment”。
Or an enchanting woman.
或者“an enchanting woman”。
Okay.
好的。
And now what about our next word?
那我们的下一个词呢？
It's a very...
这是一个非常...
And what about our next word?
那我们的下一个词呢？
It's French actually, but we use it in English.
它其实是法语词，但我们在英语中使用。
That's right.
没错。
So the critics said that this story was cliché.
所以评论家说这个故事很“cliché”。
Cliché.
“Cliché”。
Okay.
好的。
So we hear this all the time.
所以我们经常听到这个。
What is a cliché?
什么是陈词滥调？
Well, basically, a cliché is a phrase or an idea that is used so often that it loses
嗯，基本上，陈词滥调是一个短语或想法，因为使用得太频繁而失去
its meaning or importance or interest.
它的意义、重要性或趣味性。
Okay.
好的。
So can you give us some examples of a cliché moment or maybe a phrase that's cliché?
那你能给我们举一些陈词滥调的例子吗，比如某个场景或短语？
Okay.
好的。
Well, how about this one?
嗯，这个怎么样？
When you're breaking up with your boyfriend and you say, honey, it's not you.
当你和男朋友分手时说，亲爱的，不是你的问题。
It's me.
是我的问题。
Okay.
好的。
That's cliché.
这就是陈词滥调。
It's typical.
很典型。
Yeah.
是啊。
Or maybe a cliché portrayal of a French man would be a guy riding a bike with a baguette,
或者一个陈词滥调的法国人形象，可能是一个骑着自行车、拿着法棍面包、
smoking a cigarette and with a beret on his head.
抽着烟、戴着贝雷帽的家伙。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a cliché portrayal.
所以这是一种陈词滥调的描绘。
Very good.
非常好。
So it's common.
所以它很常见。
It's even to a certain point a little bit stereotypical.
甚至在一定程度上有点刻板印象。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And what about our last word?
那我们的最后一个词呢？
Well, they describe this story as a fable.
嗯，他们把这个故事描述为一个寓言。
Fable.
寓言。
A fable.
一个寓言。
Okay.
好的。
So when we were small, we all read fables.
所以我们小时候都读过寓言。
That's right.
没错。
They are stories about animals that are used to teach people a lesson.
它们是用动物故事来教人们道理。
Okay.
好的。
So a fable teaches you a lesson.
所以寓言是教你一个道理。
I think the most famous one is the one of the tortoise and the hare, right?
我觉得最著名的是龟兔赛跑，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
And another good one would be the three little pigs.
另一个好例子是三只小猪。
Okay.
好的。
That's also a fable.
那也是一个寓言。
Yep.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
So we've looked at these five great words and now it's time for us to move on to putting
那么我们已经看了这五个很棒的词，现在是时候进入下一步，把它们
it together.
组合起来。
Putting it together.
Okay.
好的。
Here we're going to look at some phrases that you can use in a bunch of different ways to
这里我们要看一些短语，你可以用多种不同的方式
help you criticize or give your opinion about a piece of art, like a movie or a book or
来批评或发表你对一件艺术品的看法，比如电影、书或
whatever.
其他什么。
Okay.
好的。
Let's start with our first word.
让我们从第一个词开始。
So the film critic asked, what is your impression of this film?
所以影评人问，你对这部电影的印象是什么？
What's your impression of?
你对……的印象是什么？
What's your impression of something, right?
你对某事的印象是什么，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So before we get into explaining impression, let's listen to some more examples.
在我们开始解释“印象”之前，让我们先听一些更多的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I don't know where, but I have the impression that we've met before.
我不知道在哪里，但我有印象我们以前见过。
Example two.
例子二。
I get the impression that he's a very organized person.
我得到的印象是他是一个很有条理的人。
Example three.
例子三。
Somehow Jim got the impression that I was gay.
不知怎么的，吉姆以为我是同性恋。
Did you tell him that?
你告诉他了吗？
Okay.
好的。
So I can see that this means basically, what's your opinion or how do you feel about something?
所以我能看出这基本上意味着，你的看法是什么，或者你对某事感觉如何？
Okay.
好的。
So you can have an impression of something or of someone.
所以你可以对某事或某人有印象。
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好的。
And what about the next word?
那下一个词呢？
Well, the critic Richard Clark said that it was a really enjoyable film even despite the
嗯，评论家里查德·克拉克说，即使有
accusations of plagiarism.
抄袭的指控，这也是一部非常令人愉快的电影。
Okay.
好的。
So now we have an interesting phrase here.
所以现在我们有一个有趣的短语。
The accusations of plagiarism.
抄袭的指控。
Accusations of plagiarism.
Okay.
好的。
So accusations is a noun, right?
所以“指控”是一个名词，对吧？
Right.
对。
It's the action of accusing.
这是指控的行为。
Okay.
好的。
Of blaming somebody.
指责某人。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好的。
And what about plagiarism?
那“抄袭”呢？
This is an academic term.
这是一个学术术语。
If you plagiarize, you copy someone's work and take credit for it.
如果你抄袭，你复制别人的作品并据为己有。
Okay.
好的。
So if I copy somebody's book and I say I wrote it, then that's plagiarism.
所以如果我复制别人的书，然后说是我写的，那就是抄袭。
Yeah.
是的。
That's pretty bad.
那挺糟糕的。
So accusations of plagiarism.
所以“抄袭的指控”。
Now we can use this phrase, accusations of something in a bunch of different ways.
现在我们可以用多种不同的方式使用这个短语，“对某事的指控”。
So Marco, let's have an example.
所以马可，让我们举个例子。
All right.
好的。
So for example, we can say he was cleared of all accusations of tax evasion.
比如，我们可以说他被洗清了所有逃税的指控。
Okay.
好的。
He denied accusations of cheating on his wife.
他否认了出轨的指控。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So accusations.
所以“指控”。
And now moving on to the final part of putting it together, we have this word lacks.
现在进入“组合起来”的最后一部分，我们有这个词“缺乏”。
The film lacks a certain originality.
这部电影缺乏一定的原创性。
Okay.
好的。
So the film lacks a certain originality.
所以这部电影缺乏一定的原创性。
What does he mean by that?
他这么说是什么意思？
It doesn't have enough of.
它没有足够的东西。
Okay.
好的。
So if you are lacking something, you don't have enough of it.
所以如果你缺乏某样东西，你就没有足够它。
Or you don't have it at all.
或者你根本没有它。
All right.
好的。
So can you give us some more examples of how we can use lack?
那你能给我们一些更多关于如何使用“缺乏”的例子吗？
Okay.
好的。
So the same way it's used in the dialogue, our team lacks the appropriate talent to complete
就像对话中使用的那样，我们的团队缺乏完成这个项目所需的合适人才。
this project.
Okay.
好的。
Or I can say, our school lacks infrastructure for so many students.
或者我可以说，我们学校缺乏容纳这么多学生的基础设施。
Or we can also say, infrastructure is lacking at our school.
或者我们也可以说，我们学校的基础设施不足。
Okay.
好的。
So you can use it in those two ways, right?
所以你可以用这两种方式使用它，对吧？
You can use it as a gerund or as a verb.
你可以把它用作动名词或动词。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Lots of great language here.
这里有很多很棒的语言。
Let's hear it one more time in context with the dialogue.
让我们在对话的上下文中再听一次。
Welcome back movie lovers to another premiere movie review.
欢迎回来，电影爱好者们，来到另一场首映电影评论。
My name is Richard Clark and I am joined today by the very erudite David Watson.
我是里查德·克拉克，今天和我一起的是非常博学的大卫·沃森。
Thank you, Dick.
谢谢你，迪克。
Today we're going to talk about the movie Lion King.
今天我们要讨论电影《狮子王》。
Tell me what is your impression of this film?
告诉我你对这部电影的印象是什么？
Well, I think this film is simply a fable.
嗯，我认为这部电影只是一个寓言。
Rising man's eternal greed for power.
揭示了人类对权力永恒的贪婪。
And in my opinion, it's a very fine film.
在我看来，这是一部非常好的电影。
Even despite the accusations of plagiarism of traditional folk tales from other countries,
即使有抄袭其他国家传统民间故事的指控，
the musical score was amazing.
配乐也很棒。
The animation was very well done and the story was simply enchanting.
动画做得很好，故事也很迷人。
I think otherwise, even though the animation was technically strong and as you say, the
我不同意，尽管动画技术上很强，而且如你所说，
score and songs performed by Elton John were great.
埃尔顿·约翰表演的配乐和歌曲很棒。
The film lacks certain originality.
这部电影缺乏一定的原创性。
It lacked heart.
它缺乏灵魂。
And I would dare to say it was too predictable.
我敢说它太 predictable 了。
Predictable?
可预测？
How?
怎么讲？
Come on, Dave.
得了吧，戴夫。
It's a G-rated movie.
这是一部 G 级电影。
It's for the kids.
是给孩子们看的。
It's not a thriller.
不是惊悚片。
Well, that's just it.
嗯，问题就在这儿。
It did have some very dramatic and intense scenes.
它确实有一些非常戏剧化和紧张的场景。
For example, when Mufasa dies or the dark, grim portrayal of Scar.
比如，当木法沙去世时，或者刀疤黑暗、阴森的刻画。
Even so, the film is linear.
即便如此，这部电影是线性的。
Mufasa dies, Simba runs away thinking it's his fault, falls in love and returns to retake
木法沙死了，辛巴逃跑以为是自己错，坠入爱河，然后回来夺回
what's rightfully his.
本该属于他的东西。
It's just too cliche.
这太老套了。
How can it be cliche?
怎么会老套呢？
It's a fable.
这是一个寓言。
It's telling a time-honored story.
它在讲述一个经久不衰的故事。
The movie makes a point of how the hunger for power is a part of the story.
这部电影强调了权力欲望是故事的一部分。
It's a fable.
这是一个寓言。
You have always been so soft, Dick.
你一直这么心软，迪克。
Open your heart, Dave.
敞开心扉，戴夫。
Don't shut us out.
别把我们拒之门外。
Anyway, that's all for today, folks.
总之，各位，今天就到这里。
Join us next time as we talk about How to Lose a Guy in 10 Days.
下次加入我们，我们将讨论《十天甩掉一个男人》。
I'm sure you'll love that one, Dick.
我相信你会喜欢那部的，迪克。
All right, so a good movie.
好的，所以一部好电影。
What do you think about The Lion King?
你对《狮子王》怎么看？
What do you think about his critique?
你对他的评论怎么看？
Well, I am with Dick on this one.
嗯，我这次站在迪克这边。
I think that this is a great film.
我认为这是一部很棒的电影。
It was one of my favorites and I've seen it about five billion times.
它是我最喜欢的之一，我大概看了五十亿遍。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
You really liked it?
你真的喜欢它？
But I'm not interested in my opinion.
但我不在乎我的看法。
I want to hear criticisms and film criticisms from our users.
我想听到来自我们用户的批评和电影评论。
Right.
对。
So come to our website at EnglishPod.com where you can leave your questions, your comments,
所以来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在那里你可以留下你的问题、你的评论，
and also any criticisms on this particular movie or maybe the other one that we mentioned,
以及对这部特定电影或我们提到的另一部电影的任何批评，
How to Lose a Guy in 10 Days.
《十天甩掉一个男人》。
Personally, not so fond of that one, but looking forward to hearing from our users.
个人来说，我不太喜欢那部，但期待听到我们用户的意见。
All right.
好的。
Or maybe any other movies you might like.
或者也许任何其他你可能喜欢的电影。
So come to the website and until next time.
所以来网站吧，下次再见。
Goodbye.
再见。
I'll watch Kill Bill at the end.
我最后会看《杀死比尔》。